Register of the Karl August Wittfogel papers, 1728-1992
Hoover Institution Archives
- UNFINISHED WRITING PROJECTS, 1956-1984
  - "Chinese Communism: Collected Studies on Modern Chinese History and Society," 1956-1966. Typescript and annotated printed copies of previously published writings
    - Section I: Studies on the History of the Chinese Communist Party
      - Soviet Strategy and the Chinese Communist Party: Significant Correlations (Folder 6)
    - Section II: Studies on Mao Tse-tung (also called Volume or Chapter V)
      - Mao: Myth and Reality (Folder 7-8)
      - Mao's Participation in the First Communist Attempt to Use the Chinese Nationalist Movement (Folder 9-10)
      - Mao's Participation in the First Communist Attempt to Use the Chinese Nationalist Movement (Box 134, Folder 1-2)
      - Mao's Use of Contradictions (Folder 3)
      - The Legend of Maoism (Folder 4)
      - Some Remarks on Mao's Handling of Concepts and Problems of Dialectics (Folder 5)
    - Section III: Studies on Chinese Communist Society (Volume or Chapter VI)
      - Food and Society in China (Folder 6)
      - From Land Reform to Collectivization (Folder 7)
      - Forced Labor in Communist China (Folder 8-9)
      - The Economic Crisis in Communist China and Its Effect on Peking's Political and Military Strength (Folder 10)
  - "Marx: Roots and Contradictions of Communist Doctrine and Strategy," 1962-1965 (by mid-1965, KAW decided to devote one volume to "The Young Marx" and one to "Marx: Roots and Contradictions of Communist Totalitarianism")
    - Notes (Box 135, Folder 1-4)
    - Outlines (Folder 5-6)
    - Holograph fragment (Folder 7)
    - Typescript
      - Undated (Folder 8-9)
      - 1962-1963 (Folder 10-14)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 136, Folder 1-11)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Folder 12)
  - "Marx/Mao," 1962
    - Notes (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Typescript (Folder 2-5)
  - "Marxism, Anarchism, and the Nihilist Revolution," 1968-1977
    - General (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Notes. Includes research material
      - Undated (Folder 2-3)
      - 1968 (Folder 4)
      - 1969 (Folder 5)
      - 1973 (Folder 6)
      - 1975 (Folder 7)
      - Bakunin (Folder 8)
      - Wagner (Folder 9-11)
    - Outlines
      - Undated (Folder 12-13)
      - 1969
        - January 22 (Folder 14)
        - April 17 (Folder 15)
        - October 23 (Folder 16)
      - 1970 (Folder 17)
      - 1972 (Folder 18)
      - 1974 October 8 (Folder 19)
      - 1974-1975 (Folder 20)
    - Holograph (Folder 21)
    - Holograph (Box 139, Folder 1-2)
    - Typescript. In part holograph
      - Undated (Folder 3-21)
      - Undated (Box 140, Folder 1-3)
      - 1968-1975 (Folder 4-10)
      - 1968-1975 (Box 141, Folder 1-8)
      - 1968-1975 (Box 142, Folder 1-10)
      - 1969
        - January 27 (Box 143, Folder 1)
        - June 17 (Folder 2)
      - 1972 March 24 (Folder 3)
      - 1972-1973 (Folder 4)
      - 1973
        - February 18 (Folder 5)
        - July 30 (Folder 6)
      - 1974? (Folder 7-8)
      - 1974
        - October (Folder 9-11)
        - November (Folder 12)
        - December (Folder 13)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 144, Folder 1-2)
      - 1977 (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (re Wagner) (Folder 4)
  - "On Dialectical Materialism," 1963. Typescript
    - Idealism and Materialism (Chapter I) (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - The Communist Dialectic of Contradictions (Chapter II) (Folder 2-5)
    - Shifting Targets of the Strategy of Contradictions (Chapter III) (Folder 6)
  - "A Rebel Becomes a Revolutionary (1911-1921)," n.d.
    - Outline (Folder 7)
    - Chronology (Folder 8)
    - Typescript (Folder 9-10)
  - "The Unknown Marx and Beyond," 1984
    - Notes (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
    - Holograph (Folder 3-9)
    - Typescript (Folder 10)
  - "The Unselected Works of Mao Tse-tung," 1965-1968
    - General (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Format of KAW's introduction to individual works by Mao (Folder 2)
    - List of documents (Folder 3)
    - Notes (Folder 4-5)
    - Typed translations of documents
      - General (Folder 6-13)
      - General (Box 148, Folder 1-8)
      - General (Box 149, Folder 1-8)
      - With accompanying introductions
        - Resolutions of the Ninth Conference of Representatives of the Fourth Red Army of the Chinese Communist Party (unlisted) (Box 150, Folder 1)
        - Comments on Friedrich Paulsen's A System of Ethics (no. 1) (Folder 2)
        - The Study of Physical Education (no.2) (Folder 3-4)
        - The Manifesto of the Hsiang-chiang P'ing-lun (no.3) (Folder 5-6)
        - The Great Alliance (no.4) (Folder 7-11)
        - Miss Chao's Suicide (no.5) (Folder 12-13)
        - Letters to Members of the Hsin-ming Hsuem-hui (no.6) (Folder 14-15)
        - Documents of the First Congress of the Chinese Communist Party (no.7) (Box 151, Folder 1)
        - A Letter to the Editor of Ta Kung Pao (no.8) (Folder 2)
        - The Peking Coup d'Etat and the Merchants (no.9) (Folder 3-4)
        - Provincial Constitutionalism (no.10) (Folder 5)
        - The British and Liang Ju-hao (no.11) (Folder 6-7)
        - The Cigarette Tax (no.12) (Folder 8-9)
        - Two Remarks Made by Mao at the First National Congress of the Kuomintang (no.13) (Folder 10-11)
        - On the Resolution on Propaganda (no.14) (Folder 12-13)
        - First and Second Analysis (nos. 15 and 16)) (Folder 14-16)
        - The Sufferings of the Chinese Peasantry (no.17) (Folder 17-18)
        - The Hunan Report (no.18) (Folder 19)
        - Why Is It that Red Power Can Exist in China? (no. 20) (Folder 20)
        - Chingkang Mountains (no.21) (Folder 21)
        - The Lin Piao Letter (no.23) (Folder 22-23)
    - Bibliographical notes (Folder 24)
- COURSE MATERIAL, 1943-1970
  - General
    - General (Box 152, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography (Folder 2)
    - Unidentified lecture notes (Folder 3)
  - Columbia University
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Annual report of the University Committee on Oriental Studies, 1965-1966. Typescript (Folder 5)
    - Courses taught
      - Oriental Humanities V3400y, n.d. Reading assignment list (Folder 6)
      - Lecture notes, 1943-1944 (Folder 7)
      - University Seminar, the State: Its Bureaucratic Aspects, 1944-1945
        - Bibliography (Folder 8)
        - Lecture notes. Includes KAW's notes and bibliography on Pharaonic Egypt (Folder 9-10)
      - University Seminar 401-402, the State, 1945-1946. Lecture notes (Folder 11)
      - University Seminar 401-402, the State, 1946-1947. Lecture notes (Folder 12)
      - Oriental Studies V3507x, 1964-1965. Syllabus, lecture notes, and student papers (Folder 13)
  - Harvard University
    - Regional Studies I: China, 1946-1947. Syllabus, reading list, and lecture notes (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Regional Studies 201: China, 1947, Summer. Syllabus and reading list (Folder 2)
    - China Program, 1947-1948. Draft syllabus (Folder 3)
    - Social Sciences III: History of Far Eastern Civilization, 1961-1962. Syllabus. Course given by Professor John King Fairbank and Assistant Professor Craig (Folder 4)
  - Saint Anthony's College, Oxford University. Seminar in Far Eastern Studies, 1970 (Folder 5)
  - University of Washington
    - General
      - Clippings, 1951-1959 (Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Recommendations (Folder 8)
      - Course critique, 1966 (Folder 9)
    - Courses taught
      - Far Eastern Studies 168: Russia and Asia, 1950 Reading list and lecture notes (Folder 10-11)
      - Far Eastern Studies 401-402: Marx, Lenin and Mao, 1962-1966
        - Bibliography (Folder 12)
        - Grade sheets (Folder 13)
        - Lecture notes
          - Far Eastern Studies 401-402, combined (Folder 14-16)
          - Far Eastern Studies 401 (Box 154, Folder 1-2)
          - Far Eastern Studies 402 (Folder 3-4)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1797-1987
  - General
    - Published materials. Includes articles and clippings (Box 155, Folder 1-6)
    - Published materials. Includes articles and clippings (Box 156, Folder 1-2)
    - Resumes and curricula vitae (Folder 3)
    - Unpublished materials (Folder 4)
  - Africa (Folder 5)
  - Agriculture
    - General (Folder 6-7)
    - Asia (Folder 8)
    - Australia (Folder 9)
    - Central America (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Chile (Folder 2)
    - China (Folder 3-7)
    - Czechoslovakia (Box 158, Folder 1)
    - Egypt (Folder 2-3)
    - German Democratic Republic (Folder 4)
    - Great Britain (Folder 5)
    - India (Folder 6)
    - Iran (Folder 7)
    - Italy (Folder 8)
    - Japan (Folder 9)
    - Korea (Folder 10)
    - Latin America (Folder 11)
    - Netherlands (Folder 12)
    - New Guinea (Folder 13)
    - North America (Folder 14)
    - Oceania (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Peru (Folder 2)
    - Polynesia (Folder 3)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 4)
    - United States (Folder 5-6)
  - Albania (Folder 7)
  - Algeria (Folder 8)
  - Amerasia Case (Folder 9)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Folder 10)
  - American Jewish Council (Folder 11)
  - Anarchism
    - General (Folder 12-13)
    - General (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - China (Folder 2)
  - Anarcho-Syndicalism (Folder 3)
  - Anthropology
    - General (Folder 4-8)
    - General (Box 161, Folder 1-3)
    - Africa (Folder 4)
    - Australia (Folder 5)
    - Borneo (Folder 6)
    - Canada (Folder 7)
    - Central America (Folder 8-9)
    - Central America (Box 162, Folder 1)
    - China (Folder 2)
    - Cook Islands (Folder 3)
    - India (Folder 4)
    - Japan (Folder 5)
    - Latin America (Folder 6)
    - Middle East (Folder 7)
    - Netherlands (Folder 8)
    - New Zealand (Folder 9)
    - Philippines (Folder 10)
    - Polynesia (Folder 11)
    - Samoa (Folder 12)
    - Scandinavia (Folder 13)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 14)
    - Tahiti (Folder 15)
    - United States (Folder 16-17)
    - United States (Box 163, Folder 1-2)
  - Anti-communism (Folder 3)
  - Archeology
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Australia (Folder 5)
    - Bulgaria (Folder 6)
    - Central America (Folder 7)
    - Central Asia (Folder 8)
    - China (Folder 9)
    - China (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Great Britain (Folder 2)
    - India (Folder 3)
    - Kenya (Folder 4)
    - Latin America (Folder 5)
    - Middle East (Folder 6)
    - Peru (Folder 7)
    - Polynesia (Folder 8)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 9)
    - Syria (Folder 10)
    - Turkey (Folder 11)
    - United States (Folder 12)
  - Arendt, Hannah (Folder 13)
  - Asia
    - General (Folder 14-15)
    - General (Box 165, Folder 1-3)
    - History (Folder 4-5)
  - Asiatic mode of production (Folder 6)
  - Asiatic mode of production (Box 166, Folder 1-3)
  - Association for Asian Studies (Folder 4)
  - Ataturk, Kemal (Folder 5)
  - Austria - History (Folder 6)
  - Australia
    - General (Folder 7-8)
    - News Weekly (Folder 9)
  - Author's Guild (Folder 10)
  - Babeuf, Francois Noel (Box 167, Folder 1)
  - Bakunin, Michael
    - General. Includes photocopied holograph of "The Life of Michael Bakunin" by Max Nettlau (Folder 2-6)
    - General (Box 168, Folder 1-6)
    - Correspondence (Folder 7)
    - Speeches and writings (Box 169, Folder 1-3)
    - Relationship with Sergei Nechaev. See also Nechaev, Sergei (Folder 4)
  - Barnouw, Victor (Folder 5)
  - Bauer, Bruno
    - General (Folder 6-7)
    - Correspondence (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - Writings (Folder 2-4)
  - Bayle, Pierre (Folder 5)
  - Beccaria, Cesare (Folder 6)
  - Benes, Eduard (Folder 7)
  - Berlin, 1961 (Folder 8)
  - Berlioz, Hector (Folder 9)
  - Berman, Ronald (Folder 10)
  - Berve, Helmut (Folder 11)
  - Bibliographies
    - General (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Anarchy (Folder 2)
    - Asia (Folder 3)
    - China (Folder 4-7)
    - China (Box 172, Folder 1-3)
    - Czechoslovakia (Folder 4)
    - Far East (Folder 5)
    - India (Folder 6)
    - Japan (Folder 7)
    - Korea (Folder 8)
    - Marx, Karl (Folder 9)
    - Socialism (Folder 10)
    - Southeast Asia (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 2)
    - Vietnam (Folder 3)
  - Borchardt, Julian (Folder 4)
  - Borodin, M. M. (Folder 5)
  - Boston Planning Corporation (Folder 6)
  - Botany (Folder 7)
  - Braun, Otto (Folder 8)
  - Brecht, Bertolt (Folder 9)
  - Brezhnev Doctrine (Folder 10)
  - Browder, Earl (Folder 11)
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew (Folder 12)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr. (Folder 13)
  - Bulgaria (Folder 14)
  - Burma (Folder 15)
  - Byzantium (Folder 16)
  - Cabet, Etienne (Folder 17)
  - Cambodia (Folder 18)
  - Camps
    - Concentration
      - General (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - Auschwitz (Folder 2)
      - Belsen (Folder 3)
      - Buchenwald (Folder 4)
    - Labor
      - General (Folder 5-6)
      - China (Folder 7)
      - Romania (Folder 8)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 9)
  - Canada (Folder 10)
  - Capitalism (Folder 11)
  - Castro, Fidel (Folder 12)
  - Central America (Folder 13)
  - Central Asia (Folder 14)
  - Ceylon (Folder 15)
  - Chapiro, Dr. (Folder 16)
  - Chernov, V. M. (Box 175, Folder 1)
  - Chiang Kai-shek (Folder 2)
  - China
    - General. Includes the General Pocket Dictionary (Folder 3-5)
    - General (Box 176, Folder 1-5)
    - General (Box 177, Folder 1-7)
    - General (Box 178, Folder 1-2)
    - Clippings (Folder 3)
    - History
      - General (Folder 4-6)
      - General (Box 179, Folder 1-5)
      - Yin Dynasty, 1400 B.C. (Folder 6)
      - Han Dynasty, 202 B.C.-220 A.D. (Folder 7-8)
      - Tang Dynasty, 618-907 (Box 180, Folder 1)
      - Ming Dynasty, 1368-1644 (Folder 2)
      - Tai Ping Rebellion, 1850-1864 (Folder 3)
      - Revolution, 1911 (Folder 4)
      - Kuomintang, 1924-1945 (Folder 5)
      - Nanchang Revolt, 1927 (Folder 6)
      - Cultural Revolution, 1965-1968 (Folder 7)
    - Neue China, Das (Folder 8)
    - Opposition to the communists (Folder 9)
  - Chou En-lai
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Speeches and writings (Folder 11)
  - Christianity (Box 181, Folder 1-2)
  - Colonialism
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Asia (Folder 4)
    - India (Folder 5)
  - Comintern. See Communist International
  - Committee for a Free China (Folder 6)
  - Committee of One Million (Folder 7)
  - Communes
    - General (Folder 8)
    - China (Folder 9)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 10)
  - Communism
    - Nineteenth century (Folder 11)
    - Twentieth century
      - General (Box 182, Folder 1-4)
      - Africa (Folder 5)
      - China (Folder 6)
      - China (Box 183, Folder 1-6)
      - China (Box 184, Folder 1-3)
      - Far East (Folder 4)
      - Indonesia (Folder 5)
      - Korea (Folder 6)
      - Latin America (Folder 7)
      - Malaya (Folder 8)
      - Religion (Folder 9)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 10)
      - United States (Box 185, Folder 1-4)
      - Vietnam (Folder 5)
  - Communist International (Comintern) (Folder 6)
  - Communist parties
    - General (Folder 7)
    - China (Folder 8)
    - China (Box 186, Folder 1-3)
    - India (Folder 4)
    - Indonesia (Folder 5)
    - Netherlands (Folder 6)
    - Poland (Folder 7)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 8-9)
    - United States (Box 187, Folder 1)
  - Condorcet, Marie-Jean (Folder 2)
  - Congress for Cultural Freedom (Folder 3)
  - Conservatism (Folder 4)
  - Constas, Helen (Folder 5)
  - Cuba (Folder 6)
  - Czechoslovakia
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Clippings (Folder 8)
  - Democracy
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Japan (Folder 10)
  - Democratic Labor Party (Australia) (Folder 11)
  - Demography - China (Folder 12)
  - Despotism (Folder 13)
  - Detente (Folder 14)
  - Deutsche Volksecho, Das (Folder 15)
  - Dodd, Thomas J. (Folder 16)
  - Donovan, William J. (Folder 17)
  - Dutschke, Rudi (Folder 18)
- East Asia. See Far East
  - Economic policy
    - General (Box 188, Folder 1-2)
    - Asia (Folder 3)
    - China
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Domestic (Folder 5)
      - Domestic (Box 189, Folder 1-6)
      - Domestic (Box 190, Folder 1)
      - International (Folder 2)
    - France (Folder 3)
    - Germany - Third Reich (Folder 4)
    - India (Folder 5)
    - Israel (Folder 6)
    - Japan (Folder 7)
    - Mexico (Folder 8)
    - Middle East (Folder 9)
    - Polynesia (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 2-7)
    - Taiwan (Folder 8)
    - Turkey (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - United States (Folder 2)
  - Education
    - General (Folder 3)
    - Australia (Folder 4)
    - China (Folder 5-6)
    - Germany
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Friedrich Wilhelm Universitat (Folder 8)
      - International Institut fur Sozialforschung an der Universitat Frankfurt am Main (Folder 9-11)
    - Great Britain (Box 193, Folder 1)
    - New Guinea (Folder 2)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 3)
    - United States (Folder 4-5)
  - Egypt (Folder 6-7)
  - Energy (Folder 8)
  - Engels, Friedrich - Writings. See also Marx, Karl (Folder 9)
  - Engineering (Folder 10)
  - Epstein, Julius (Folder 11)
  - Espionage
    - Arnold-Baumer case (Folder 12)
    - Canada (Box 194, Folder 1)
  - Estonia (Folder 2)
  - Etymology
    - General (Folder 3)
    - American Indian (Folder 4)
    - Arabic (Folder 5)
    - Chinese (Folder 6-7)
    - Dravidian (Folder 8)
    - Latin (Box 195, Folder 1)
    - Oriental (Folder 2)
    - Persian (Folder 3)
    - Polish (Folder 4)
    - Sanskrit (Folder 5)
    - Slavic (Folder 6)
    - Socialist vocabulary (Folder 7)
    - Turkic (Folder 8-9)
  - Europe
    - General (Folder 10)
    - Eastern (Folder 11)
  - European Economic Community (EEC) (Folder 12)
  - Fairbank, John K. (Folder 13)
  - Fascism
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Japan (Folder 15)
  - Far East (Folder 16)
  - Far East (Box 196, Folder 1-4)
  - Far Eastern Notes (Folder 5)
  - Feltrinelli, Giangiacomo (Folder 6)
  - Feudalism
    - General (Folder 7)
    - Russian (Folder 8)
  - Feuer, Lewis S. (Folder 9)
  - Foreign aid (Folder 10)
  - Foreign relations
    - Australia
      - General (Folder 11)
      - United States (Folder 12)
    - China
      - General (Box 197, Folder 1-2)
      - Africa (Folder 3-4)
      - Burma (Folder 5)
      - Cuba (Folder 6)
      - Far East (Folder 7)
      - Germany (Folder 8)
      - Great Britain (Folder 9)
      - Indonesia (Folder 10)
      - Israel (Folder 11)
      - Japan (Folder 12)
      - Japan (Box 198, Folder 1)
      - Korea (Folder 2)
      - Latin America (Folder 3)
      - Soviet Union
        - General (Folder 4-7)
        - General (Box 199, Folder 1)
        - Sino-Soviet Conflict (Folder 2-4)
      - Taiwan (Folder 5)
      - Turkey (Folder 6)
      - United Nations (Folder 7)
      - United States (Folder 8-10)
      - United States (Box 200, Folder 1)
      - Vietnam (Folder 2)
    - France
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Africa
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Algeria (Folder 5)
        - Tunisia (Folder 6)
      - Vietnam (Folder 7)
    - Great Britain
      - Asia (Folder 8)
      - China. See Foreign relations - China
      - South Africa (Folder 9)
      - Soviet Union (Folder 10)
    - Greece - Yalta Conference (Folder 11)
    - India - Pakistan (Folder 12)
    - Japan
      - General (Folder 13)
      - China. See Foreign relations - China
      - Philippines (Folder 14)
      - Russia/Soviet Union (Folder 15)
      - United States. See Foreign relations - United States
    - Philippines
      - Japan. See Foreign relations - Japan
      - United Nations (Folder 16)
    - Poland
      - Czechoslovakia (Folder 17)
      - German Democratic Republic (Folder 18)
    - Soviet Union
      - General (Folder 19)
      - Afghanistan (Folder 20)
      - China. See Foreign relations - China
      - Ethiopia (Folder 21)
      - Germany
        - Weimar Republic (Folder 22)
        - Third Reich (Folder 23)
        - Federal Republic (Box 201, Folder 1)
      - Hungary (Folder 2)
      - Middle East (Folder 3)
      - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) (Folder 4)
      - Turkey (Folder 5)
      - United States (Folder 6-7)
    - United States
      - General (Folder 8)
      - Asia
        - General (Folder 9)
        - Far East (Folder 10)
        - Southeast (Folder 11)
      - Australia. See Foreign relations - Australia
      - China. See Foreign relations - China
      - Cuba (Folder 12)
      - Europe
        - General (Folder 13)
        - East Central (Folder 14)
      - Germany - Empire (Folder 15)
      - Iran (Folder 16)
      - Japan (Box 202, Folder 1)
      - Korea (Folder 2)
      - Latin America (Folder 3)
      - Mexico (Folder 4)
      - Soviet Union. See Foreign relations - Soviet Union
      - Taiwan (Folder 5)
    - Vietnam
      - China. See Foreign relations - China
      - Far East (Folder 6)
      - France. See Foreign relations - France
      - Malaya (Folder 7)
      - Taiwan (Folder 8)
  - Fourier, Charles (Folder 9)
  - France
    - General (Folder 10)
    - History (Folder 11)
  - Free Press (Folder 12)
  - Frederick II, the Great, King of Prussia, 1740-1786 (Folder 13)
  - Fromm, Erich (Folder 14)
  - Fuhrmann, Ernst (Folder 15)
  - Fulbright, J. W. (Folder 16)
  - Gandhi, Indira (Folder 17)
  - Gandhi, Mohandas (Folder 18)
  - Germany
    - General (Folder 19)
    - Federal Republic of Germany (Folder 20)
    - German Deomcratic Republic (Folder 21)
    - History
      - General (Box 203, Folder 1)
      - Weimar Republic (Folder 2)
      - Third Reich (Folder 3)
  - Ghana (Folder 4)
  - Great Britain (Folder 5)
  - Greece (Folder 6)
  - Grimm, Baron de (Folder 7)
  - Guevara, Ernesto (Che). Includes writings (Folder 8)
  - Hallische Jahrbucher (Folder 9)
  - Haubach, Theodor (Folder 10)
  - Health services
    - General (Folder 11)
    - China (Folder 12)
    - Japan (Folder 13)
    - New Guinea (Folder 14)
    - Philippines (Folder 15)
    - Soviet Union (Folder 16)
    - United States (Folder 17)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 18)
  - Hegel, Georg F. W. (Folder 19)
  - Heine, Heinrich (Folder 20)
  - Heinzen, Karl - Memoirs (Folder 21)
  - Hellenistic Age (Box 204, Folder 1)
  - Helvetius, M. (Folder 2-5)
  - Herzen, Alexander (Folder 6)
  - Herzen, Natalie (Folder 7)
  - Hiller, Kurt (Folder 8)
  - Himmler, Heinrich (Folder 9)
  - Hiss, Alger (Box 205, Folder 1)
  - History - general (Folder 2-3)
  - Hitler, Adolf (Folder 4)
  - Hong Kong (Folder 5)
  - Human rights
    - General (Folder 6)
    - Eastern Europe (Folder 7)
    - United States (Folder 8-9)
  - Hungary
    - General (Folder 10)
    - 1956 (Folder 11)
  - Ideology (political)
    - General (Folder 12)
    - China (Box 206, Folder 1)
    - Democratic socialism (Folder 2)
  - India
    - General (Folder 3-4)
    - History (Folder 5)
  - Indonesia
    - General (Folder 6)
    - History
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Revolution of 1963 (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (Folder 2-4)
  - Internal security - United States (Folder 5)
  - International, The
    - First, 1864-1878 (Folder 6)
    - Second, 1889-1914 (Folder 7)
    - Third. See Communist International (Comintern)
  - International Congress of Orientalists (Folder 8)
  - International law (Folder 9)
  - International Press Correspondence - Table of contents, 1928-1929, 1936 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - International relations
    - Military (Folder 2)
    - Political (Folder 3-6)
  - Iran (Folder 7)
  - Islam (Folder 8)
  - Israel (Box 209, Folder 1)
  - Italy (Folder 2)
  - "Jack the Ripper" (Folder 3)
  - Japan
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Clippings (Folder 5)
    - History (Folder 6)
  - Japan Democratic Socialist Party (Folder 7)
  - Jewish Socialist Community (Folder 8)
  - Jews (Folder 9-11)
  - Judicial systems
    - General (Folder 12)
    - Buddhist (Box 210, Folder 1)
    - Chinese (Folder 2-3)
    - French (Folder 4)
    - German (Folder 5-7)
    - Indonesian (Folder 8)
    - Italian (Folder 9)
    - Japanese (Box 211, Folder 1)
    - Pakistani (Folder 2)
    - Soviet (Folder 3-4)
  - Karpovich, Michael (Folder 5)
  - Kashmir (Folder 6)
  - Katyn Massacre (Folder 7)
  - Kautsky, Karl (Folder 8)
  - Kennan, George F. (Folder 9)
  - Kennedy, John F. (Folder 10)
  - Khrushchev, Nikita (Folder 11)